hey what's up welcome to the grow Your
Life podcast my name is Jeremy Krakowski
and on this podcast I help coaches
trainers mentors and speakers make more
money get more clients and scale their
businesses now I'm excited today I want
to talk about something that I've
noticed is a problem that I haven't
addressed a whole lot and part of it is
because I myself even struggled with
this
and I would full disclaimer tell you
that I would not claim to be at the top
of the mountain having all the solutions
to this but there are some things that I
have learned and some things that I feel
more confident today in
than I ever have
and that is that you have to break free
from this thinking
that
lack and living in lack
and living without and below your means
and not having enough time or money or
resources is a
just a lot in life that you're given and
that that's how things are always going
to be because that's how they've always
been
and that it's a it's a badge of honor
and that you just have to figure out how
to make it work within the bounds of
those limitations this thinking
is often summed up in and is called the
poverty mindset
and what it is it's a mindset that's
rooted in
lack poverty don't have enough there's
not enough there's not enough to go
around
you know if I if I gain I'm taking away
from somebody else
it manifests in a number of different
ways the number one way that I see it
manifest though
um with coaches and mentors and trainers
and I've seen it in my coaching groups
is people
they will hear all the strategies about
how to get clients how to grow a
business how to make six and seven
figures
and the first thing they say is well I
don't really have a whole lot of money
to be able to do that sort of stuff
or I don't have enough time
to be able to
work on getting clients
or you know I just don't know enough
even that lack of knowledge it's all
tied to lack and when you shift your
thinking into an abundance mindset
a mindset of there will always be enough
I always have enough
and even now listen I I I do believe
time is a valuable resource
and we need to be disciplined with our
time
and we're not promised tomorrow
so I understand that so this is not to
conflict with that
but there's this thinking of
rush rush rush
through things instead of letting things
take their time
and
realizing that you have enough time to
accomplish the goals that you have
now that doesn't mean that we're going
to be lazy and we're going to sit around
and we're gonna do nothing okay so you
hold those two ideas in your mind at the
same time as not that you have a lack of
time but actually that you have enough
time and that you can get done
everything you need to in the time that
you have and what this does is this
comes from a place of gratitude this
comes from a place of you looking at
your life
and and I was challenged with this by
looking at my own life and how I was
complaining about my lack of time while
having
a wonderful
newborn child in my life
five month old right now
and the the last time that I have right
now and I noticed I was complaining
about how much I lacked
and you know two years ago I was
complaining about how I didn't have
enough financial resources to actually
start to grow my business
now in the present reality that you live
in that might be true
like logically that might be true
okay so we're not we're not denying
we're not going into denial about what
we're experiencing
but we're not letting it Define us and
be the lens and filter through which we
make our decisions
to where your present reality is not the
lens and filter through which you make
your decisions
and what this takes is this takes
stepping out in faith even when you have
no guarantee or certainty of how things
are going to turn out even when you
don't have all the resources but you
start declaring and you start believing
and you start living and making
decisions in your business as if you
have all the resources that you want
again not condoning going into a bunch
of debt and being stupid
not at all
see it's funny people conflate good
advice with what they believe I might be
saying so that's why I have to kind of
explain and explain like what I mean by
this what I mean is that when you go out
there sure it might be your last 300
right now to run this campaign
but be okay if it doesn't produce the
result that you want and realize that
you can always go out there and get more
money
there's always more money that you can
get that you can become resourceful that
you are resourceful
and stop declaring and living in
lack I don't have enough time I don't
have enough money I don't have enough of
what I need to do the things
that I feel called to do
that's one of the biggest blocks that we
can end up putting up in our lives
is believing that we don't have enough
of something
and that is rooted in the poverty
mindset
and so what you want is you want an
abundance mindset and a mindset that
there is always more than enough there's
always another day there's always
another opportunity there's always
another chance there's always another
moment
um
and and when I say that instantly our
brain goes into yes but time is finite
and tomorrow is not promised and all
this all these things that sound great
right
but when it comes to the reality of you
actually taking action in your business
they're not going to help you by
focusing on
the fact that okay I'm not promised
tomorrow that can motivate me to take
action
but I'm not going to kill myself
nor am I going to
feel negative and complain about how
little time I have left and that be the
focus of my energy no my energy needs to
be focused on what am I building today
with the time that I have and how can I
make the most out of the resources that
I have and it's going to be amazing and
it's going to be incredible and I'm so
excited to see what happens and I'm so
excited to see what comes out of this it
might not be perfect but it's gonna be
worth it that is a shift in your
thinking
and you've got to shift away from
I see it all the time
I'll talk to somebody 80 to 90 percent
of what comes out of their mouth is I
don't have enough money to make my
business work
that's all they're focused on
that's all they're focused on I don't
have enough
I don't have enough
I don't have enough I need something
different to happen in my life and
external circumstance in order to to
create my life and this is a victim
mentality that you are a victim to your
circumstance and when it combines with
the poverty mindset the chances of you
succeeding in your business are very
small now I have seen people succeed I
have
but your energy is going to be so
focused on
operating within the boundaries of what
you don't have instead of creatively
thinking so you might have an idea when
you're in an abundance mindset that will
actually pull you out of the lacked
mindset I want to give you an example of
this it's just
like
crazy
is if you're so focused on what you
don't have or you don't have what you
don't have You're Gonna Miss
opportunities for how you can make the
most out of what the resources you do
have because you're wishing the
situation was different
and then when you get into the situation
hindsight is always 20 20.
you know we put in an offer into our
house this week
and our our just getting personal here
but our
our rent in our current house not that
we can't afford it but you know it our
our lease ends in November
and I was like man we're gonna have to
come up you know four months of rent on
top of the mortgage
and then it dawned on me after I put the
offer in literally I've been thinking
about that even stressing about it for
over a year subconsciously the lack lack
mindset and as after I put in the offer
I realized wait a sec
if we close in July they're not going to
ask for the first payment till September
that's only two rent payments
and yet I was worried about that
I've had that happen numerous times
where I catastrophize and worry about
and try to manage and try to make sure
to manage and hold it all together with
the limited resources that I have
instead of just going after the goal
plowing forward moving forward
and making the best of it and enjoying
the process
when you start to do that it unlocks
Pathways in your brain of creativity
that are legitimately blocked
from thinking out of a lens of a well I
don't have enough time money connections
resource mindset and you have to change
that thinking in order for the
creativity to come through in your brain
and now your actions will actually start
to follow that and that will produce
more you know the old phrase man the
rich always just get richer and richer
and richer well it's because they're
operating out of that abundance mindset
it's not actually because they have a
ton of resources
hmm
now telling you that as somebody who's
been on the up the sides are broke and
the sides of rich
it's how you think
and your creativity because you will
become resourceful when it's important
enough to you
but most people won't
and most people will fight for their
limitations and they'll fight for what's
not working and they'll fight for their
lack
and they'll argue for what they don't
have access to instead of realizing all
the abundance that's right in front of
them
and so I want you to shift
into an abundance mindset even if
everything in your life is telling you
otherwise
start to put on what would it feel like
if I had all the financial resources
that I needed
what would it feel like for everything
to start going the way that I wanted it
to
even if manifest in your life it's not
being able to experience that will start
to put your brain in a way of it'll
start to become more creative and the
neurotransmitters and Pathways will
start to come up with ideas
for how to actually work within your
current situation which is incredible
from operating from a mental creative
lens of abundance and so this is why
we need no help to go towards the worst
case scenario as human beings our brains
just automatically do it
we have to be intentional to say you
know what yeah
thanks for that but I'm not gonna Focus
my brainwave energy on what's not going
how I wish it should be could be would
be that would help me and I'm going to
focus on the dream the goal the vision
the future that may not be exactly
what's in front of me right now but that
I know is possible for me and I'm going
to start to live from that reality of
the future from the reality of abundance
instead of out of lack out of what I
don't have and you'll be amazed how
quickly things start to come together
for you
I've seen it happen in my life I've seen
it happen in so many other people's
lives
this is one of the biggest secrets
behind a lot of the success and the
successful people that you know
that's not to knock strategy the
strategies are important but I've seen
people have all the strategies
even have all the resources
and still operate out of the poverty
mindset as a lady I met I coached her a
while back
she was afraid to spend 300 on Facebook
ads when she had a multi-million dollar
stocks portfolio because she didn't want
to waste money
to try out an offer to test something
out
and and I just like it gripped her in
fear of it not working
you got to break up with this it's a
it's a way that our brains are wired
and it's often through pain and Trauma
and situations is why it gets wired that
way but we got to be intentional to
shift out of it to start to see
ourselves living in abundance
living from a future where we have
everything that we've ever wanted
and then we start to make decisions from
that perspective into our present
reality and watch things shift for you
all right
I know that this is going to help you I
know this is going to help some somebody
[Music]
[Applause]